[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
hello good evening good day everybody
and welcome once again to the ask a
visit Show episode 158 I hope you're all
doing very well
and today we have a whole bunch of
questions that I have selected I I'm
sure I have selected more than I can
answer but let's see how many how many I
can answer before we do that let me see
who all is there who all is present in
attendance on the live chat I can see
shorya Sagar Dr a ayushman Mishra om
kamlesh
sabarinat Rohit Martian Mukesh
foreign
again
and a million other people and Darth
plague is the dev ayushman chirag Arnav
uh thank you so much all of you for
being on the live chat with me tonight
and with that done
let me get into the questions let's take
a whole lot of questions as many as you
can as we can today question number one
is by Swati the Antarctic ocean eyes
reached a record Law recently and the
Arctic is also melting four times faster
than the rest of the world what do you
think will be the impact of these
changes
well so you're talking about climate
change the global warming phenomenon
that we are all witnessing climate
change is a reality in case some people
don't know climate change has always
been a reality as long as this planet
has existed
the
um millions of years ago see our planet
was formed about 4.5 billion years
before today uh about 100 million years
after the formation of the solar system
and originally it was a hellishly hot in
a planet with a very toxic atmosphere
and it's evolved a lot ever since life
first emerged 3.77 billion years ago and
lots has changed after them so right now
we are going through a phase of global
warming uh ice sheets are melting
Glaciers are melting so what's gonna be
the consequence and the impact of these
changes eventually the sea levels will
rise so in the past sea levels have
risen and Fallen about 10 000 years ago
uh 12 000 years ago uh these sea levels
were much lower than what they are today
and India and Sri Lanka were connected
as a single landmass Sri Lanka was part
of the Indian subcontinent it was
connected to the Indian subcontinent
Indonesia the archipelago of Indonesia
was connected to the Asian mainland and
so on and there may most likely even was
a land route to Australia through
Indonesia so that's when the sea levels
were significantly lower maybe 120 150
kilo meters lower than where they are
today
uh now the ocean levels are going to
rise because of the global warming so
what's going to happen is that the low
level parts of the low lying parts of
the world will get submerged eventually
over the next Century Two centuries
maybe maybe the next 50 years maybe the
next 20 years some of them uh Nations
like uh the Maldives will cease to exist
they will get submerged uh and uh the
same thing Could Happen will happen
eventually in the sundarbans region of
Bangladesh so lots of territories lots
of such regions will get engulfed by the
ocean they will go under the under the
ocean so
um yes the the Contours
of the world of the earth of the nations
of the coastal regions will change
that's going to be the impact of these
changes and it's going to cause human
migrations and problems and issues which
we will have to learn how to deal with
so we are right now in the initial phase
of this if you look at photographs of
let's say the Statue of Liberty taken a
century I mean taken let's say at the
turn of the 20th century in the
beginning of the 20th century and you
see photographs taken today there is no
real appreciable discernible rise in the
sea level so right now we are still kind
of where we were 100 years ago but
eventually it's gonna start affecting
the sea levels and the sea levels will
rise in low-lying parts of the of the
planet will get submerged eventually so
that's going to be the impact of these
changes
Muhammad yakub Khan says why does the
Indian government not issue free
downloadable Indian map on their website
or direct Google to do that because it
is still difficult to find authentic
Indian maps and many organizations and
even Nations show the wrong map of India
yes lots of Nations show the wrong map
of India
even Nations like let's say Israel Etc
if you see their
map of India is depicted incorrectly it
represents uh
thinks the way they actually are as
opposed to India's territorial claims
some parts of India are currently
temporarily occupied by certain other
nations it's a matter of time and before
we get them back maybe more that's a
whole different story so the question is
why doesn't the Indian government issue
a free downloadable Indian map correct
they correct eating map well I actually
it does have it let me uh share that
the map the correct map of India
wherever can you find it I think it's
called the Survey of India
give me a second let me let me locate
that
uh where do we where can we find it
the political map of India let me share
that on the screen
okay
the political map so there is this
website called the Survey of India it's
an Indian government website it's part
of the government of India and it has
the political map of India it's uh
available in three different languages
Hindi English and Sanskrit let's take a
look at the Hindi map click on this
okay it's opening in a new
tab let's open it over here so here you
have the correct map of India in Hindi
right you go back and you can see the
same thing in let's say Sanskrit or
English let's open the sunscreen version
of the map of India
it's showing Western India here it's
showing uh Eastern India east coast of
India
foreign and so on right so the correct
map of India is indeed available online
I would say suggest to the government of
India please do a better job of
publicizing this so that people know how
to find it but in case you don't know
you can just search for this Survey of
India on Google go to Google type in
Survey of India map
of India and you will be able to locate
this page hopefully it will not be too
hard so that's what we need to do if you
if you want to see the correct accurate
map of India uh that's what we do so
that's the solution right now obviously
if you look at Google and all they show
various different interpretations of the
map of India if you go to Google dot
Google Maps the Indian version it will
show the correct map of India to some
extent but if you go to Google The
Google maps.com maps.google.com it will
show the incorrect map of India that is
the situation right now but the correct
map is indeed available
recent targeted killings of terrorists
in Pakistan and training of Taliban
regime officers in India do you find any
coincidence is there exchange of deal is
there is there an exchange deal you
eliminate our enemies and we will train
your people what's your take on this
my take on this is that in the
government of India does not indulge in
any activities that would support
terrorism we do not do that we will uh
help the the current government of
Afghanistan which is the Taliban
government when it comes to diplomatic
activities Etc so let's let's see what
the what kind of cooperation
Etc is happening let me put that on the
screen I'm sure we can find something
Taliban training diplomacy all that
stuff
uh here we are so here's the news that
we hear
India to train Taliban in diplomacy
students from Thailand and Malaysia
attending as well
so the mea has launched a four days
Diplomat training course which will see
the presence of diplomats from the
Taliban
um immersing with Indian thoughts and
India immersion program
and this will be this course will be
imported to various students from
various countries by the Indian
Institute of Management Kohli code
cozy code I don't know how to say it
yeah it's Koli code uh here's a
different report of that Taliban which
is out to India Embassy to train Afghan
students Afghan diplomats in Kabul so
this seems to be a different thing
the embassy maybe the the the the
trainee diplomats will come to the
Indian Embassy in Kabul and maybe the
thing will be uh available online for
them maybe that's a possibility it's a
four-day training program for Abraham
foreign Ministry officials in Kabul
beginning Tuesday I'm not sure which
Tuesday this is from March 14th
and uh clarification from Delhi follows
the course is fully online and will be
conducted by the IIM kolikode it's not
as if somebody will be coming to India
for it okay so these two Taliban
students the Afghan students will do it
from Afghanistan itself may be available
to come to the Indian Embassy in Kabul
to uh get access to this four day
trading program so that is the kind of
uh
training the government of India will
provide to these uh aspiring diplomats
from Afghanistan who are part of the
Taliban government so uh that's
definitely what's happening when it
comes to terrorism India will never
support terrorism India will not um see
there are nations that support terrorism
Pakistan obviously is a terrorist regime
it's a terrorist Nation it has been
indulging in various terrorist
activities in India for decades and
which nations supported Pakistan well I
can think of two major Nations that have
supported Pakistan mainly it was the
United States the United States financed
and funded Pakistani terrorism in India
for decades later on China also took
part in this and they also supported
Pakistani uh terrorist activities
against India
India this is a line that India won't
cross this is my official statement I'm
not giving you any unofficial statement
here right so India does not condone any
form of terrorism India will not support
any form of terrorism we condemn all
form of forms of terrorism and uh yes so
the the extent to which we will
cooperate with the Taliban
it it is up to it's limited to
over-the-board activities diplomacy and
things like that okay and economic
cooperation uh economic aid to
Afghanistan that much so that is my take
on this India does not support terrorism
arush Mahajan says as India sent a big
help to Turkey after the earthquake the
recent uh terrible earthquakes uh but
still turkey betrayed us in the United
Nations and they supported Pakistan why
look please understand my dear friends
there was no agreement between India and
turkey that we send you Aid and you
support us in the United Nations there
was no such agreement when you say that
someone betrayed you it means that they
there was an agreement and they went
against the agreement that's the
definition of a betrayal you had a deal
you had an agreement you had a contract
and then they broke it that's called a
betrayal when India sent Aid to Turkey
there was no such agreement
India did this of its own volition India
did this voluntarily turkey appealed to
the entire world for Aid and India was
one of the first Nations to respond
India sent a whole lot of Aid India also
sent trained Personnel for rescue
operations India sent a whole bunch of
doctors to set up field hospitals and
treat the survivors that's what India
did and India did this without any
expectation of something in return that
is what we have to understand let's not
get emotional and say the Turks betrayed
us we know what turkey's geopolitical
stand is we know what what sort of
ideology you could say turkey espouses
and we know what nations turkey supports
turkey has been a long long-standing
long time supporter of Pakistan it has
certain compulsions geopolitical
compulsions religious compulsions which
compelled Turkish politicians to support
Pakistan
right so there was no agreement between
India and turkey that you're gonna stop
doing this once we send you the aid
India did this on its own volition why
does India does do such things why then
the question that arises is why does
India help Nations that are that are
going to be ungrateful supposedly and
and not reciprocate towards India well
understand how the world works you have
to
build a trek track record
of being morally right see the United
States keeps on harping
about about human rights and democracy
it will say that we have consistently
supported and promoted human rights and
democracy and yes verbally they have
supported it promoted human rights and
democracy for decades their actions are
totally contrary to that claim they have
been propping up uh dictatorships all
across Africa they have conducted so
many regime change operations across the
world they recently tried it in Georgia
they've done that in Ukraine they will
they will interfere in the internal
affairs of various Nations including
India
and their human rights record well but
they keep on verbally
supporting and promoting human rights
and democracy so they can claim that
they have consistently supported and
promoted human rights and democracy so
India is also now building a genuine
track record of actually through actions
supporting other nations when the
coronavirus pandemic hit us
India was the only large Nation major
relation to send to send vaccines free
of cost to other nations when the U.S
would send the vaccines they would
expect they wanted money in exchange
so what the Americans call AID is
actually sales on the other hand India
sent vaccines the Indian vaccine that
actually works not the American vaccine
India sent the non-dangerous vaccine to
various
poor and hard-hit Nations without
expecting anything written without
asking for any payment so India is
building this track record what does it
do for India in the long run it will
it will help the world understand what
India is all about it will ensure that
the world trusts India because India is
poised to rise now I have spoken about
this before I spoke about it yesterday
China this is no longer China Century
China's century is already over the only
nation that has any chance in this
Century to surpass the U.S economically
and otherwise is India only one nation
and when we rise we're already Rising
when we rise we don't want the world to
fear us so we have to send signals to
the world that we are not like China an
expansionist power a hegemonic power a
rapacious power
we do not seek to
to exploit you
right so we have to do these things to
send that message across we have to do
it again and again over and over again
to reinforce the message
so we we did that when the coronavirus
pandemic happened we we helped as many
nations as possible without asking for
money in return and when it comes to
these calamities we are willing to help
even Nations that are very strongly
anti-india like turkey on humanitarian
grounds
so when India genuinely Rises and we
will need the world to cooperate with us
there will be hopefully willing to
cooperate with us willingly without
doubting our intentions when China
approaches a nation for cooperation
the people doubt what the true you know
they they wonder what the true uh
intentions are
with India it will not happen so that's
the reason why India does these things
we are investing in India's long-term
future
okay so yes we we do spend taxpayer
money on these things it's going to
benefit the nation in the long run
don't look at the world from a
short-term window look at it from a big
picture perspective so for once
for the first time since 1947 we have a
government that thinks long term that
thinks long term that's what we're
witnessing in action so let's not get
all emotional and wonder why the
government is wasting taxpayer money and
let's not accuse the Turks of of
betraying India we know exactly what
they're going to do and they have not
surprised us they did exactly what we
expected them to do that's fine we don't
want anything in return from them we are
building a track record we are building
like they say you know you build a
resume right you do the right things and
you build a resume so India is building
it's geopolitical resume that's what we
are doing
Oscar
great achievement yes let's Rejoice the
song was indeed awesome from All Points
of View yes I heard it was shot in
Ukraine in front of the presidential
Palace do you think the Ukraine angle
had something to do with the Oscar or is
it linked with India's Rising stature in
the world let's find out what this is
all about let us go to uh good old
Google search
Google isn't a threat disease but let's
go there
um
all right Google plain all Google search
and let's let's search for na2 na2
notunaku and look look at the images so
here we have these two gentlemen doing
the famous dance and there's this
building in the background you see some
of it here you see it here you see it
over here this is a yeah there you have
it so take a look at the building you
know you can see what it looks like the
characteristics of the building now
let's search for uh Kiev
presidential Palace
all right Google tries to correct the
spelling that's fine so it's the same
building as you can see it is the same
building indeed
so what happened is that this song the
song and dance sequence was shot in
front it was filmed in front in the
courtyard in in the in the courtyard of
the Palace of the Ukrainian presidential
Palace where the great Shri zelinsky uh
resides
and this obviously this filming was done
before the the hostilities broke broke
off broke out
the Ukraine War began the special
military operation was ordered by Mr
Putin so this entire filming was done
before that
so you are indeed right that this uh
this entire sequence was shot
in in in the courtyard of the
presidential Palace and that's the
building that you see in the background
so the question is do you think the
Ukraine angle has anything to do with
Oscar
I don't think that uh the Oscar was
given to the song because the Ukrainian
presidential Palace was in the
background and I don't think it was
given because NATO NATO sounds like NATO
NATO that's also not the case even
though it's a nice joke
um I what I really think is that uh see
now it's it's
pretty much clear
that in the long run the next 20 30
years India is going to surpass China
and eventually India will surpass the us
as the largest economy so uh to the West
wants India on its side then they want
to give uh Awards and and recognition to
some aspects of Indian Cinema so as to
enamor Indians uh with the women they
want Indians to feel favorably about the
west and they know that Indians love
foreign recognition especially Western
recognition if an African nation or or
or or let's say Indonesia or somebody
gives Awards to
to Indian Cinema Indians are not that
induced but if it's the if it's the West
that does it then Indians are all you
know they rejoice and dance in the
streets so Indians still have this
inferiority complex so they want to uh
take advantage of that and make Indians
feel like the West is on India's side so
it's about India's Rising stature in the
world they want to capture the hearts
and minds of Indians which is very easy
to do that say a couple of good things
Indians will love you especially if you
are a person from the West there are all
these YouTube channels all these YouTube
channels of these Western Travelers who
come to India and see a couple of nice
things and Indians are like they
subscribe in millions and there are
these reaction channels from from abroad
that react to various Indian movies or
what not I don't know even even
there are people who react to me as well
you know uh so they also get millions of
subscribers so Indians crave foreign
validation especially Western validation
so it's all about that it's it's about
leveraging that so that's why these days
you will see you know I'm sure in the
future lots of Indian girls ladies will
be given Miss Universe Miss World titles
or whatever and Indian movies will get
more recognition in the west it's
because India's stature is rising and
they want to capture the hearts and
minds of Indians and it's a long-term
investment in that as well so that's
what it is all about there is a
geopolitical angle there is uh you know
this sort of angle in everything
foreign
I give you ROFL so LOL says what is the
British Indian Territory near the
Maldives good question I am sure I must
have spoken about this earlier but let's
revisit this matter
and for that we have to visit the map I
did not open the map yesterday which is
very unlike me where's the map here is
the map where's the map here's the map
right so let's find this
British Indian Territory near the
Maldives so I'm sure you know where
India is on the map let's locate the
Maldives south of India in the sea of
saurashtra which is erroneously called
the Arabian Sea so here here we have the
Maldives and the capital Mala is over
here it's less than thousand kilometers
from the Indian Coastline if we measure
the distance it's about 600 or so
kilometers from thiruvananthapuram in in
Kerala Kerala Pradesh so we have the
Maldives and if you go southwards from
the Maldives we have something that's
called a British Indian Ocean territory
so historically the Maldives were
inhabited by Indian origin people today
also they are inhabited by Indian origin
people but it's a separate nation today
it's an archipelago it's an extension of
the lakshadweep
we have the lakshadweep over here the
these islands Mali is an extension of
that and the British Indian Ocean
territory is an extension of the
Maldives it was originally inhabited by
Indian origin people and also some
people of African origin the and it's
called the shago archipelago c-h-a-g-o-s
as you can see on the screen which is a
French origin word and the people were
called the shagosians they were all
expelled from this place by the British
by the evil oppressive British occupiers
of the place and they were forced out of
this territory and most of them were
exiled to either uh reunion or Mauritius
now let's come back here and let's take
a look at this why is it this why is
this territory important let's look at
the satellite images very tiny Islands
as you can see there is one uh
this is a coral reef which with a couple
of islands over here there's more over
here
danger Island they call it over here
there are three brothers I believe Three
Brothers what is it called
these three islands are called Brothers
this is called uh I guess not I guess
not perhaps I was wrong
uh anyhow so let's come back to this
place called Diego Garcia which is the
major Island on in this territory so
this island obviously it belongs to the
British technically it's called the
British Indian Ocean territory this is
the island of Diego Garcia it has been
handed over to the Americans so if we
zoom in you will find this big
Runway over here this this airport and
if we measure the dimensions you will
find that it's in excess of three
kilometers long 3.6 kilometers long
which means that the largest and
heaviest planes can land over here this
is an American Air Force Base all right
um and you can see some Pakistani
presence here Nasi Pakistan number one
Diego Garcia it seems like a restaurant
or something over here you can see your
fuel tanks fuel the pose
what else do we have here
we have various uh restaurants and stuff
like that it's all in Indonesian for
some reason for some reason
um
there's a 7-Eleven over here in case you
know what that is there's a dinosaur
theme park so this is all run by the
Americans there is a port obviously
where is the port
here we have the port do we see anything
interesting here I guess not unless we
look closely we will not see anything
interesting
and uh in the South we have what looks
like some other residential facilities
what is this ground-based
electro-optical deep space surveillance
it's a spy station American spy station
and once again we have a Pakistani
restaurant here very interesting
so this is the British Indian Ocean
territory uh the the natives of this
region who are who are of Indian origin
and are some of some of African origin
were expelled illegally from here there
have been demanding that they be allowed
back so this is
historically it was an extension of the
Maldives which means historically it was
Indian Territory it is now occupied by
officially occupied by the British but
it's actually run by the Americans it's
one of the major air bases of the
Americans military Stations of the
Americans in the world it's it's in a
way similar to Guam in the
in in the Pacific region where is Guam
all right let's let's not go they try
and locate that right now but that's
what it is so that is the that is the
British Indian Ocean territory near the
Maldives it is a legacy of the colonial
era at some point in time it must have
been occupied by the French then it is
currently in the possession of the
British but run by the Americans it
should be free it should either be part
of Maldives or an independent nation or
if you look at the Historical president
precedent the way the Chinese do then it
should be part of India actually So
eventually it will happen we will
get it done
yadav says Australia doesn't have
nuclear weapons then why are they buying
nuclear submarines under the aukus deal
so Australia is part of the closed knit
the closest knit uh Alliance of the US
the the closest state of the US which is
the five eyes Nations the U.S plus four
more Nations Australia New Zealand
Canada and the UK
so these are the five English speaking
Nations four and the big boss which is
the U.S
now
the Australians originally had this this
uh deal with the French they were
supposed to buy French scorpion class or
whatever class submarines they had the
signed agreement agreement was signed it
was done and they broke the agreement
they backstabbed the French the French
are very upset and they have gone for
this U.S uh deal so the Americans will
be selling them five or six submarines
the deal is gonna cost them more than
360 billion dollars which is an eye
watering amount of money shocking amount
of money
and these are going to be nuclear
submarines what does it mean
that a submarine is a nuclear submarine
it doesn't mean that it's going to carry
nuclear weapons the Australians don't
have any nukes unless the Americans have
placed news on Australian soil which is
a possibility but those will be
controlled by the Americans Australia as
a nation does not have nuclear weapons
so why are they going for nuclear
submarines and what does it mean to be a
nuclear submarine a nuclear submarine is
a submarine that has a nuclear
propulsion it's engine is a nuclear
reactor
so there's a nuclear reactor inside in
which nuclear fission happens which in
turn drives a steam engine that
generates electricity and produces the
propulsion for the submarine so that's
what a nuclear submarine is so you can
have nuclear submarines without being a
nuclear weapons state
and you can be a nuclear weapon state
and not have nuclear submarines so India
could very well place a nuclear dipped
ballistic missiles on Scorpion
submarines if we can get it done and we
India also does have the arihant class
nuclear submarines two already are an
operation two are being built right now
and we will have many more in the future
you know better versions better uh more
enhanced submarines so Australia despite
being a non-nuclear urban state is going
to purchase
U.S nuclear submarines in a deal that is
in excess of 360 billion dollars that's
shocking so the advantage of nuclear
propulsion is that you can essentially
stay underwater indefinitely
and uh you can you know even even get
the oxygen and everything recycled so
you don't need to surface
for oxygen when you have
diesel engine submarines and all you
have to keep on surfacing from time to
time maybe once in a week or once in two
weeks once in three weeks depending on
the on the design to get oxygen and
replenish your cells and all those
things you also have something called
air independent propulsion and there is
a sterling cycle engines and hydrogen
few fuel cells and all that so these are
various Technologies you can use the air
independent proportion is typically
quieter than nuclear propulsion but yeah
so uh the advantage of a nuclear
submarine with nuclear proposition is
that you can stay underwater
indefinitely months at a time maybe in
excess of a year if you can carry enough
supplies and all that
um so that is why Australia is buying
nuclear submarines from the US now
there's a very nice cartoon that I
showed yesterday let me show it again uh
let's do that
so why have they actually done this the
French offer was much better perhaps for
them but this is a political cartoon
it's about uh Joe Biden talking to Rishi
sunak Joe Biden is the prime minister of
the UK and Russia tonight is the
president of the U.S
so yeah you know what I mean right Joe
Biden is the prime minister of the US
and job and and riches the president of
the UK or something like that I'm sure
you know what it is so Byron tells Rishi
he calls him Richie then Richie we told
the Aussie guy that we wanted to park
our China attack Subs in his country and
he should pay us 368 billion for the
privilege and he agreed hahaha
so essentially that's what it is the
Australians are paying America
protection money
you pay up and you're gonna be safe for
a week
so they're paying us the U.S protection
money
and the somebody's are U.S built
submarines they're extremely
technologically advanced the Australians
probably
don't have the know-how of how to
operate the submarine so most likely
even the crew will be American most
likely the captain will be American so
it's it's America parking five or six
nuclear submarines on Australian soil on
Australian Waters in Australia will pay
the Americans for the privilege that's
essentially what it is that's how the
world works yeah nice
Johan says why did the U.S bomb Japan
nearly 3 000 kilometers from the U.S
Mainland and why did the U.S not decide
to bomb Germany the leader of the Axis
powers
well it's a good question you ask you
know the the the the the uh
justification
for the nuclear bombing the nuclear
tests on Japanese civilians is that it
helped America end the war early
otherwise it would have taken several
more months for the Americans to launch
a an armed invasion of Japan it would
cost a lot of money and lots of lives
will be lost so we we were able to you
know expedite the process so it actually
was better for everybody in the from the
big picture perspective less Japanese
died less soldiers died it was better so
the question is why did they not do the
same with with Germany they could have
simply nuked Berlin
and then end of story
no Hitler no Germany end of story
Germany collapses so clearly there is
more to it than with Zion they will say
that there was a timeline the bomb
development ended only at a certain time
and only then by the time Germany was
already defeated almost defeated all
these justifications will be made but
the fact is that they decided to
test nuclear weapons on Japanese
civilians not on German civilians so
see one can only speculate as to what
the reason could be clearly there could
be a racism angle the Americans were
definitely they still are definitely a
very racist Nation nowadays obviously
black lives do matter I'm happy to see
that that uh there is there they deserve
that the Americans but historically they
have been a an extremely racist society
when the World War II happened the
second world war there were many
Japanese origin people in the United
States Japanese Americans these were all
herded into concentration camps the
Americans did that there were
concentration camps on Japan on American
soil in which were reserved exclusively
for the Japanese the non-whites
so
so there was an element of there were
German origin Americans too in the U.S
they were not touched
but the Japanese origin American
Americans were targeted and placed in
concentration camps so clearly there was
racism very very strong elements of
racism in the US at that time and until
very recently so one could definitely uh
see
in an element of racism in this
uh so yeah that's what I can tell you
and obviously Germany was much closer to
the US I'm not sure what the distance
between the U.S and Germany is but the
Western Europe was by the time to some
extent falling under U.S influence or
domination Dominion
um
so yeah there definitely was an element
of racism and the Americans decided to
Nuke the Japanese and not the Germans
Ajit says did Kush
did Maury did maurians establish the
hotan kingdom in Central Asia excellent
question what is the khota what was the
khotan kingdom let's go to the map and
I'm gonna show you a different map this
time so that we get a a different
perspective
okay let's let's put this map on the
screen
Kingdom
take a look
so the we we all recognize this map it's
a map of this Indian subcontinent and
Eurasia so the dark shaded region north
of India was the approximate region of
the hotan Kingdom so this kingdom was
founded roughly 2000
2400 or so years before today okay that
and and it existed until
the beginning of the turkic invasions of
Central Asia and India so the history of
the hothan kingdom is that it was
established by Indians
who came from murian era India
so uh the greatest emperor of the
mauryan empire was uh Ashoka Emperor
Ashok who was one of our greatest
Emperors uh in terms of power he in in
terms of the fact that he unified the
entire subcontinent under one uh under
under his political Dominion so Ashok
was one of the greatest of the modern
Emperors his he had multiple children we
obviously know about Mahendra and
sangamitra uh these two siblings he sent
to Sri Lanka to propagate dhamma we know
that he also had a son a son called
Kunal I believe Mahendra was his eldest
son but for whatever reason Mahendra was
not not in line to be the next Emperor
so Kunal was in line to be the next
Emperor but uh and the show had multiple
wives as Emperors used to have in those
days so of one of his wives who had a
different son was jealous of Kunal
wanted her son to be the emperor and she
caused Kunal to be blinded
and obviously she would not have done it
herself a number of people who were in
her employment would have done that
so Kunal was blinded and because of this
he could not become the emperor So
eventually kunal's son samprati who was
ashok's grandson became the next Emperor
now the People Who blinded Kunal
obviously it would not make Ashok happy
that his son the Crown Prince was
blinded so apparently the story goes um
we're not sure if it is entirely true
but The Story Goes at these people these
these high-ranking people were expelled
out of India north of the Himalayas and
possibly it was they who founded the
kingdom of khutan or maybe it was
somebody else but what we know is that
khutan was founded by Indians from
morian era India
and uh and then it flourished for a very
long time until the turkic invasions of
Central Asia and India which destroyed
all traces of Buddhism Hinduism and
Indian culture and presence from Central
Asia
so that's how the kingdom of khutan
ended uh
and khotan uh you know produced many
scholars and all that for instance uh
there is a very famous
a scholar
who was of Indian origin but who spent
his life in China his name was Kumar
Rajiv
so kumara Jiva was they they call him a
Buddhist monk they call him a missionary
these are all
you know
Western
perspectives he was he was a scholar in
The Vedas as well he was learned in The
Vedas as well not just in in the
Buddhist uh scriptures so uh
I believe that his father could have
been from khutan or or his father
probably was from Northern India
probably Kashmir and his mother was
probably khotanis or from Kucha or
something like that so uh very
interesting history and it was
definitely Indians who established the
khutan kingdom much of Central Asia
was Indian or indianized
there were multiple migrations out of
India before zero A.D multiple ways of
migration out of India starting from the
rigbedic times themselves
and these uh these people who went out
of India established indianized kingdoms
all across Central Asia and they kept
they they kept uh track of their lineage
and all that and many of them claimed
descent from Lord Rama and and various
other great rulers of India and it was
all all of this was the Indian presence
in Central Asia was destroyed eradicated
wiped out by the Turks the turkic
Invaders who destroyed all traces and
vestiges of Indian uh culture and
genetics to some extent from Central
Asia and today we'll find ruined
monasteries ruined temples all across
Central Asia and those are rare because
typically they would be destroyed and
something else would be built on top of
that
so yeah
saurabh says did the hicksos who
conquered Egypt around one eight zero
zero BC where the Indian Vedic people
right that's that's an open question the
uh
the origin of the hexost the the
identity of the exos who were these guys
so the hexas conquered Egypt
around
1650 BC somewhere around that time
around 1650 BC and they ruled Egypt for
about a century or so the 15th Dynasty
in Egyptian history those were the hik
sauce so these were people okay let's
take a look at the map because uh that
will help us understand what we are
talking about let us go to the map where
is the map we need the map
here is the map okay I'm I hope we all
know where Egypt is so here is Egypt the
present day modern nation state of Egypt
and as you can see it is attached
physically geographically to Asia to
what is called Western Asia so the
invasion of Egypt by these foreigners
the hicksos
happened from the northwest
the Northwest is present-day uh
the the
it's it's Israel Jordan Saudi Arabia all
of that
and as we know
around 1500 BC there were indianized
kingdoms and empires in Anatolia and
present-day Syria we know about the
mittani we know about the Hittites these
were all Indian origin rulers the these
kingdoms the majority of the people in
the Kingdom were of local origin but the
aristocracy the ruling class was Indian
they spoke sankrit and there is
unambiguous unmistakable undeniable
evidence of that and this hap this
happened just a little while after the
the conquest of Egypt by the hick source
so uh there is a possibility that there
was a connection between the indianized
kingdoms over here and the hex also
conquered Egypt and ruled for a century
so what were the Hig sauce like let's
take a look at what the hexas looked
like from Egyptian depictions of these
uh foreigners so here is one example of
how the Egyptians saw the hik sauce so
if we look to the west of the image to
the right of the image right all the way
right you will see a couple of uh
Egyptians who are wearing loin clots or
whatever it is and they are bare chested
so the the two gentlemen on the extreme
right of the image are Egyptians and the
people on the left
are all foreigners or hick sauce so you
can see that the hick sauce are depicted
as having light brown skin the Egyptians
are depicted as having dark brown skin
and the the dress that the hixels wear
is is different some of the hixsons are
bare chested some of them wear these
robe like uh outfits the hexas ladies
are are they wear these full body robes
with arms left bare and so on and they
have these animals you can see mules or
donkeys there are kids or children on on
one donkey there are weapons and
implements over here there is a double
curved bow
that one of these gentlemen is is
carrying the one on the extreme left and
he has a quiver full of arrows as well
and so on and there are some of them who
have Spears and some of them have these
curved swords
and they have other animals as well
so uh this seems to depict
these hicksauce Invaders and eventual
rulers of Egypt uh so these guys the
hicksauce they introduced lots of new
things to Egypt they introduces horses
into Egypt they introduces chariots into
Egypt these were horse riders and they
engaged in Chariot Warfare very
interesting they had spoke to Wheels
they introduced new weapons into Egypt
like those curved swords they introduced
bronze
uh technology copper technology or
bronze one of these two into Egypt they
introduced new musical instruments
and such such like and they
their religion or culture was
polytheistic in nature their greatest
God was a god of rain and thunder and
storms so the Western historians and the
consensus is that the this God is
identified with the with the uh
Mesopotamian storm God Bal b double a l
b a a l Bal but um it could also remind
you of another God the Indo-European God
which is which has different names Indra
in the oldest version and then obviously
Jupiter Zeus
Thor
Etc same God Thunderbolt
and uh
and and the hammer so it could I mean
the circumstantial evidence such as the
the composite double double curved bow
the the the uh horse riding the Chariots
the the the the Thunder God all of that
is very the circumstantial evidence does
indeed
point
to possibly a Vedic origin of these guys
but we still don't have clear and
ambiguous evidence if you can find some
skeletons of these gentlemen who are
buried uh and do some DNA analysis that
could give some uh give throw more light
maybe if you could uh compare that with
uh methane genetics if any of that is
available and obviously with Indian
genetics obviously we would need to do
more genetic research in India as well
so right now we are not quite sure we're
not quite sure right now it is
definitely possible that there could be
an Indian origin or
kind of origin of these exhausts even
though kind of come later but it could
be possibly the same people but we're
not quite sure it needs to be
investigated further by historians
geneticists scientists
Etc maybe in 10 20 years we will have a
much better picture yeah
chiching says I have noticed that
nagaland Cuisine of the Far East of or
the Far East of India Cuisine is similar
to Southeast Asian countries the cuisine
of Southeast Asian countries like
Vietnam Indonesia Etc then India's
Mainland Indians why is it so right
interesting question so uh once again
let's go back to the map and and take a
look in case our some of our viewers may
not be aware of
the Far East of India it's called the
northeast of India why is the it's why
is the Far East of India called the
northeast of India why is it so you know
when the uh British Invaders first
colonized India they their their the
first region they conquered and
colonized was Bengal
all right
bangadesh Bengal
and from their vantage point in Bengal
the Far East of India was to the
northeast of Bengal and then they wrote
research papers or books or whatever
calling these regions the northeastern
regions the Northeast
but it was the northeast of Bengal not
the north Northeast of India and later
on this
this nomenclature persisted because
India's historians who
whose greatest joy in life is to ape the
westerners they simply carried on
calling this region the Northeast even
though it's the northeast of Bengal not
the northeast of India as a whole
it's actually the east of India or the
Far East of India anyhow that's that's a
different thing that's not what the
question is about the question is about
the cuisine of nagaland and of these uh
other states in the Far East of India
like
and so on
even Assam
um mizoram and so on so if you look at
the cuisine or let's take nagaland as an
example nagaland is a wonderful place
it's in the foothills of the Himalayas
very hilly region a very nice climate
and all that very interesting uh culture
very beautiful local culture lots of
different uh tribal groups and all that
so if we see the cuisine of this region
it's very distinctive and very different
from what we find in the the no the the
what we call the mainland of India so
any cuisine is going to use local
ingredients now when you're living in a
region like nagaland it's which is hilli
which is a very cool climate usually
which is thickly forested you're gonna
use local ingredients right so the if we
look at the far East of India
geographically it is actually part of
Southeast Asia
geographically speaking it's kind of
part of Southeast Asia which is Myanmar
Thailand Laos Cambodia Vietnam all that
and the the ingredients that are used
in the cuisine the herbs and all those
things they are the ones you would find
locally and these are the the herbs and
all those things that are found in
Southeast Asia which is why if you see
the cuisine of nagaland or Manipur or
whatever they use lots of uh ingredients
which are essentially identical that to
what you would find in a market in let's
say Vietnam very similar ingredients
there's a lot of fish that is eaten
River fish not sea fish and when it
comes to nagaland there is a lot of
dependence on eating pork pork is one of
the main sources of protein
um fish also like I said there's a lot
of fermented foods that's used a lot of
boiled fruits so the style of cooking is
there's a lot of boiling
um there's the use of turmeric to some
extent a lot of red chilies are used or
local uh the the the what they call the
bhut Jolokia in Assamese the the ghost
chili extremely extremely spicy that is
used fermented bamboo shoots all of that
so it's because
these are the things that grow locally
and also because the people of this
region we don't quite know the origins
of the various tribes of nagaland of the
people of arunachal Pradesh of the
methane people of Manipur and so on uh
the the languages that are spoken in
this region are called are typically
tibeto Burman languages
so it shows a cultural and genetic and
ethnic Affinity with the people of
Southeast Asia unfortunately our
historians have not done their job so we
don't quite know where the migrations
came from so where what was the origin
of the various tribes of nagaland did
they migrate into this region right now
some how long ago did the migration
happen did it happen from Myanmar for
instance or from Yunnan that is
temporarily part of China or some other
region so
and even our geneticists have not done
the job because there is no real genetic
research done into the genetics of of
the Far East of India so the historians
have failed in doing their job in the
geneticists have failed in doing their
job so we don't quite know what is the
migratory origin of the various peoples
who live in this region but if you look
at the facial features and traditions
and all that it's clear that there is a
significant Affinity with the people of
Southeast Asia uh
so the because of these regions the
cuisine is different Cuisine is an
integral part of culture
uh so you will find lots of similarities
between the cooking between the cuisine
of nagaland Manipur
Etc other places to the cuisine in
places like Cambodia Laos Vietnam
Thailand even the Yunnan region of
present-day China the cuisine in Yunnan
also is heavily dependent on pork as a
protein that's all in in Cambodia Etc
other parts of Southeast Asia insects
are are a significant part of the diet
for instance in Cambodia uh people use
red ants to add texture and crunch and a
little bit of protein to certain meals
you know that's how it is I mean what's
wrong with that there are other insects
like silkworms Etc that are that are
eaten consumed and so on and you find
such things in some parts of of the Far
East of India as well uh in nagaland I'm
sure you you find some of that in Assam
also possibly arunachal and so on so
it's because of these regions these
reasons that the cuisine of the Far East
of India is a significantly different
from that of the uh what they call what
we call May the so-called Mainland part
of India it's much closer to the cuisine
and and culinary traditions of Southeast
Asia and Yunnan which kind of hints at
an ethnic origin of some of the some of
the tribes of this region which may lie
in those regions in maybe southeast Asia
or in Yunnan possibly but definitely not
Chinese
there is no cultural ethnic and culinary
Affinity between the people of the Far
East of India and the Han Chinese none
whatsoever the Affinity is is between
the people of forest or the forest of
India and the people of Southeast Asia
and possibility of Yunnan the people who
live in Yunnan the native inhabitants of
Yunnan which is currently a part of
China these people are actually Thai
people
they are the same ethnicity as the Thai
people and the home people the origins
of the home people very interesting
thing and unfortunately our historians
have
not done their job these are fascinating
questions that people are asking
teaching always asks very interesting
questions then none of the historians
have any answers to this because they
have done no research all they do is
teach the same old regurgitated ancient
tired beaten history that no one cares
about
and these questions are still open
questions and they have not addressed
them this far so hopefully in the coming
day coming years historians will
actually wake up especially the
historians in the Far East of India in
the universities in nagaland in Manipur
Etc they will start doing some actual
original research not just you know
what what they have been doing thus far
Rinnegan says Indian Academia wrongly
represents manipur's history uh
1814 Manipur was as big as United Bengal
uh drawn by Matthew Carey so I'm not
sure who this Matthew carry was or is
clearly some British guy or something
like that I mean the British occupier of
India in the one of their historians but
uh yeah see
I have not really seen what India's
Academia says about Manipur
but what we think of Manipur is is what
the current uh boundaries of Manipur are
the state of Manipur let's put that back
on the screen we are still talking about
the far East of India so Manipur is the
state that is to the south of nagaland
and to the east of meghalaya
and west of Myanmar or Burma that is
Manipur so today you have a certain
geographical extent of Manipur now
Manipur has been in existence for at
least 2000 years most likely 2000 to
3500 years there's this long lineage of
of Kings uh that is recorded in the
Royal Chronicle of the manipuri Kings
the cheth which most likely goes back to
3500 years before today
and money the kingdom of Manipur has
obviously over the centuries seen Rises
and falls and if you talk about uh the
data the date that renegan is saying
1814 the kingdom of Manipur was much
larger at the time so uh
1814 when did the Burmese invasion of
Manipur happen I think it happened in
1819 the Burmese invasion of Manipur so
uh you had a number of great Kings
um you had a king called uh
whose daughter was insulted by the
Burmese his daughter was supposed to
marry the Burmese king or The Prince and
when the Burmese came to receive her
they said that she's too ugly send us a
different daughter so obviously the king
will be extremely angry about that and
he ordered his son
pamayiba to go and attack the Burmese he
did that he he I believe he conquered
Rangoon Yangon and there's a sword he
threw the spear he threw his peer at the
throne
at the Throne of the king or whatever
and if the mark may still be there or
some some such stories there
um so this king called pamayiba who
lived in the 18th century is the guy who
introduced Hinduism properly vaishnavism
uh gaudia vaishnavism into Manipur and
then um
then he had a couple of sons and there
was some infighting and all that then
you had a king called chintan kongba in
the late 18th century uh he obviously uh
is also known as bhagya Chandra the guy
who set out this said about this big
Renaissance in manipuri culture he
he was a great king no doubt but he did
not leave behind a clear line of success
succession so there was a kind of Civil
War in Manipur after he died at the end
of the 18th century uh three or four
Sons came to power briefly and they
fought among each other and then you had
a guy called marjit Singh who is the the
king who was in power in Manipur until I
think the Burmese invasion of Manipur in
1819 and then the Burmese invaded
Manipur devastated Manipur seven years
of Devastation right and that is the
event these this seven years of
manipur's occupation but the burmes
which marks the downturn in the fortunes
of Manipur and even today Manipur is
suffering the consequences of that one
event
so that's how it happened that's what
happened so the the kingdom of Manipur
was much larger in the past there was a
king whose name of forget right now he
conquered parts of Yunnan which is
currently part of China
um
so yes I'm not sure what Indian Academia
has to say about Manipur I mean
manipuri Scholars and professors and
historians are part of Indian Academia
what on Earth are they doing they're
doing nothing
I know for a fact that if you go to
Manipur you will see that the the kids
are taught the same old history of the
mughals and all that and they're not
taught the history of Manipur at all
so it's a sad State of Affairs in India
uh so yes it is I I don't know what the
Indian Academy writes about Manipur but
obviously the truth is not being written
nothing is the way it used to be
so uh I hope that the manipuri Academia
Indian Academy gets gets its act
together and does some starts doing some
actual research and recording the true
history of the country yeah it's high
time we start doing that
geopolitical do bases we have temples
universities even coins and ruins of
various things of our great emperors but
do we still have palaces of the mauryan
Emperors or the cholas or the kushans or
the karkautas or the guptas where they
used to live
what a fascinating question geopolitical
Dubai has asked we have ruins ruins in
northern India of temples that date back
thousands at least
clearly more than two thousand years
we have ruins of buildings that go back
thousands of years in the the Saraswati
Sindhu region we have ruins of ancient
cities that go back five six thousand
years
yes
but when it comes to the mauryan era
which is two and a half thousand years
before today or the kushan era which is
about two thousand years before today or
the Gupta era that is 1500 years before
today or the karkota era which is about
1300 years before today roughly roughly
or the Chola you know which is just a
thousand years ago where are the great
palaces of these great Kings we have
forts
to some extent we have a fort in where
is it batinda or something which was
built by kanishka but that's a fort it's
not a palace a fort is not a palace a
fort is a fortified building with a
Garrison of soldiers inside and all
those things
so first of all Indians tend to conflate
the two a fort is a palace no forts are
not palaces so when it comes to the more
years the capital was partly Putra
which is present-day Patna and the ruins
of partly Buddha are kind of outside in
the vicinity of present-day Patna
so
there is no Palace there
is no Palace we know that some of the
greatest Emperors of our country of our
civilization were the maurians
Etc
where why is there no Palace there
the cushions
where they also had an incredible uh
incredibly powerful Empire
the greatest of the questions his Empire
touched the shores of the Caspian Sea
and the Aral Sea it also included the
entirety of presentation
whatever it's called in China in Chinese
and of course much of India
so such a powerful emperor who had two
capitals
uh one was I believe mathura and one was
purushpur which is present-day Peshawar
where are the Palaces
where is kanishka's Palace why is there
no Palace
the Gupta Emperors they were some of the
greatest Emperors of all time
and their Capital was partly Putra
initially and then later on it's
somewhere else um where was it mathura
was it somewhere else but anyhow there's
no Gupta Palace anywhere
dynasty was a short-lived Dynasty based
out of Srinagar where is the Palace
one of the greatest conquerors of all
time he conquered much of Central Asia
and Tibet
versus Palace why is there no Palace in
Sri Lanka there's a temple on a hill
from the shankarachary hill in Srinagar
there's no Palace
I mean we know that turkic Invaders
wanted to destroy all the temples and
still the temples temples tend to stand
to some extent
we still know where the ruins of the
universities are
but where are the Palaces the cholas the
cholas conquered the whole of Southeast
Asia all the way to the Philippines
surely they would have had palaces where
are the Palaces what I'm trying to tell
you my dear friends is that Indian
Emperors and Kings did not have palaces
their Duty their Raja Dharma or Dharma
itself was to serve the nation the
civilization and the people it was not
to amass wealth for themselves they
would typically have lived in reasonably
humble abodes obviously there will be a
lot of fortification there'll be a lot
of security
and when you receive foreign dignitaries
in all ambassadors and all you have to
have a certain amount of dignity
and opulence but still they did not live
in palaces
and this is something you see even in
recent times the marathas had this
enormous Empire they liberated India
more or less from the Turks
did they live in palaces they had
something called shanivar Vada which was
a fortified encampment
it was not there was no Palace as such
it was not a palace there was obviously
some element of luxury and all that but
it was not a palace
when it comes to the great Queen
did she live in a palace no she lived in
a modest house that house still stands
so that's what I'm trying to tell you
Indian Kings no matter in Emperors no
matter how great and how powerful they
were
they do not build opulent palaces and
show that they were at a different level
from the ordinary humans and all that
try to prove me wrong find me any
evidence of kushan palace's mauryan
palaces Chola palaces karkuta Palace or
whatever you will not find any
hardik says I have watched all of your Q
and A streams thank you sir thank you
very much I really appreciate it hardik
uh and never asked the question well
here's a question the question is what's
going on in Israel there's news of
anti-government protests due to judicial
bill
do you think that the West is trying to
do a regime change operation in Israel
through a Judicial coup very interesting
question so currently the prime minister
of Israel is Mr Benjamin Netanyahu I
believe it is his fifth or sixth term as
prime minister
so
he is viewed as a very uh nationalistic
prime minister uh someone who has a
robust internal and foreign policy he is
viewed as a very right-wing politician
and leader
um and there's a very strong influence
of the left in Israel's politics these
days uh Israel's governance system
ruling system is in it's the
parliamentary system which is kind of a
copy and knockoff of the British
Westminster system kind of what we have
in India today and historically if you
look at the past 10 governments or so
you will say that most of them have been
Coalition governments
so it's a very unstable system for some
reason that's how Israel has been
designed very unstable system always a
coalition government always negotiations
and compromises and all that and prime
ministers typically well they tend to
not last the full term you know five
years or whatever the term is I think
it's five years
so prime minister's Prime Ministers come
and go you had
I forget the names was it no no no no no
no not the guy sorry uh who was the
Prime Minister
I think it was and then you had the
naftali Bennett and various other people
who've come and gone come and go gone
few months so now who is back
and now he has introduced this bill
uh to reform the judicial system in
Israel so let's take a look at the
judicial system in Israel what is it
like shall we find out
it's interesting
and let's find out why he wants to
reform this so about the Supreme Court
of Israel the Supreme Court consists of
15 justices that number is established
by the knesset which is the parliament
of Israel
and has varied over the years uh the
most senior justice as designated
president of the court in the next
senior Justice is Deputy president
justices and all other Israeli judges
are appointed by something called the
judicial selection committee okay that's
the body that appoints Israeli judges it
is a body composed of three Supreme
Court judges
two cabinet ministers
two parliamentarians and two
representatives of the Israeli Bar
Association let's take a different look
at this
okay the
um
this committee
it has
two members of the Bar Association
the Chief Justice and two other judges
which makes it five
and then two parliamentarians
and two ministers
so there are five people from from the
Judiciary and four people from the
parliament
which means that the Judiciary dominates
this body
all right so uh the judicial selection
Committee in Israel is dominated by the
Judiciary the Judiciary Is Not Elected
by by anyone
so it's kind of the Judiciary appointing
itself it reminds you of a certain Other
Nation doesn't it
which nation would that be a Wonder so
in Israel the judicial there is some say
for the Justice Minister and the cabinet
minister and two parliamentarians but if
the Judiciary sticks together they can
every time get their thing done and
appoint people of their choice so
essentially in Israel you have an
unelected Judiciary which keeps
appointing itself
that's the situation all right and in
Israel the thing is that the Judiciary
has the
power
to strike down any law
that the uh
Israeli Parliament passes by saying that
it's unconstitutional or whatever even
though the the nation of Israel does not
have a written Constitution but the
Judiciary can do it if it so desires
so there is an unelected Judiciary in
Israel with a veto or Parliament
so the Parliament can pass a law and the
Judiciary can strike it down saying that
it's unconstitutional or whatever
that's a problem
the people have to be Supreme in any
Nation not unelected judges I'm talking
about Israeli all right Israel I'm not
talking about anything else
so that's the problem so now what
Benjamin Netanyahu has done is that he's
introduced uh a bill or bills or
whatever it is which seeks to redress
this problem
it's going to give Parliament
uh more say in appointing the judges of
the Judiciary and secondly it will take
away to a large extent the judiciary's
power to strike down any lower Act of
parliament so if the Judiciary says
something then the parliament votes in
majority against whatever the Judiciary
is saying then the parliament will be
Supreme
a simple majority is all that will
suffice so because this Netanya who has
introduced this new legislation there
suddenly what has happened in Israel is
that there are these massive protests
thousands of people protesting
they are saying that uh then that
Netanyahu is trying to end the
independence of the Judiciary I'm sure
we've heard that somewhere before yes so
hundreds of thousands of Israeli
protectors protesters have appeared
overnight
overnight spontaneously apparently but
well-organized protesters
well-coordinated protests but somehow
it's spontaneous apparently
that is what is happening and you will
find people like Yuval nawal Harari who
are part of the western liberal cabal
who are protesting against Netanyahu
and they are also trying to trying to
bring in the Palestine issue that we are
not only protesting against the judicial
thing but also about Palestine that
Israel greets Palestinians badly or
whatever
but the main thing is that they are
trying to secure and they're trying to
ensure the continuation of the supremacy
of the unelected Judiciary in Israel
which obviously is kind of undemocratic
so Netanyahu actually is trying to bring
more democracy into Israel
but these protesters are saying that you
are trying to uh try to trying to end
the independence of the Judiciary and
end the system of checks and balances
and all those things
so uh the question is who is organizing
these protests who is coordinating
everything who is funding everything now
we know that Israel
is is a very close we could call it a
lie of the US a very close relationship
between Israel and Israel in the US lots
of American citizens have also also have
Israeli citizenship citizenship dual
citizenship
lots of Israeli origin people Jewish
people are are in very powerful
positions in the U.S
so
and and Israel has essentially been the
the West's linchpin in the Middle East
region in keeping the entire region
unstable and keeping the Arab Arab
Nations
balanced out under check under Threat
all the time
so that they can keep supplying oil
quietly
so Israel is very important control of
Israel is very important for the U.S
so one of the ways of controlling a
nation see you can control the
politicians but when you have an
unstable system
which is by Design unstable where you
have Coalition governments that come and
go come and go then it makes more sense
to
control in organ of the government that
is more stable
which is ideally unelected like the
Judiciary
so it is possible one could say one
could you know we have seen lots of
regime page operations color revolutions
and all that these organized so-called
spontaneous protests in Israel show the
same characteristics as let's say the
maidan revolution in in
Ukraine or the recent uh color
Revolution attempt in Georgia suddenly
spontaneously thousands of people appear
and they start protesting in a very
coordinated fashion against the
government
show a force on the streets Street power
that is typically what happens in these
U.S mediated regime operations worldwide
so yeah it it has all the all the
Hallmarks of a
of a you know
us mediated color Revolution
so the the US would like the Judiciary
to remain uh more powerful more powerful
than the parliament of Israel that way
they can control uh the proceedings and
and the the the direction in which the
nation goes in the long run on the long
run
so it is a possibility I'm not saying it
is the case the possibility definitely
exists do we have evidence that it's be
all being done
from the US we have no evidence of that
but look at the pattern of the past 20
years all the color revolutions that
have happened this what's happening in
Israel shows the same pattern but that
is not conclusive evidence so we don't
have conclusive evidence but there is a
pattern which strongly suggests it could
be a continuation of what the US has
been done has been doing in other
nations so yes it is possible
that the West is trying to do a regime
change operation in Israel through a
Judicial coup but I have no evidence of
that we don't have any evidence of that
it is definitely a possibility the
possibility cannot be ruled out
Daniel Nicholson says amongst the great
the global powers that includes India
none of the nations are democratic and
the true sense of the term is it even
possible to even dream of becoming a
dominant civilization with our current
current Democratic setup is it about
time to change our real Democratic setup
and shift into a one-party almost
elected autocratic system
okay let's look at the history of the
20th century there were two two
superpowers
two superpowers
the US and the USSR the USSR was very
clearly an autocracy a one-party State
no democracy no elections elections if
they were held were kind of sham
elections so that is a naked autocracy a
naked dictatorship look at the U.S
now it's very become very clear now that
the Pentagon has more power than the
White House
the Pentagon recently blocked the White
House attempt the white White House's
attempt to go to to help the
international criminal court uh build a
case against Vladimir Putin so the White
House is the elected government and
President of the U.S and what Joe Biden
and his and his administration was
trying to do the Pentagon the military
establishment blocked it
which clearly tells you that the
military establishment the unelected
invisible military establishment of the
U.S is more powerful than the president
and the elected government of the U.S
so the relationship between the Pentagon
and the White House is essentially
identical to the relationship between
Rawalpindi which is the Pakistan
military in Islamabad which is the
Pakistani Parliament and prime minister
the U.S is nothing but a much stronger
greater larger and more efficient
efficient form of Pakistan
and obviously you have elections and you
have presidents who come and go all that
is fine
and the US is a two-party system
you only have two real parties if you
want to come to power you have to be in
one of the two political parties there
are other parties that exist nominally
but they actually don't matter at all so
it's a two-party system the U.S is a
two-party state which is just one step
above a one-party system like North
Korea or communist China
so essentially the US is an autocracy
masquerading as a democracy
the USSR was a naked autocracy so the
two great superpowers of the 20th
century were autocracies then a new
great power emerged which is not a
superpower by any means it's a great
power it's China communist China this
again is a one-party State it's a naked
autocracy
if you look at the history of the 20th
and 21st century until now you had have
had three great Powers two superpowers
and one great power all three are
autocracies
that tells you something
Now liquid look at the history of the
world the last 2000 years all the great
powers that came and went were Empires
an Empire is it autocracy it's a
dictatorship
Rome was an Empire it was not an not a
democratic setup it was they had
emperors
um the Ottoman Empire again Empire look
at the history of India whenever India
was at its peak the Pinnacle it was the
mauryan Empire The kushan Empire the
Gupta Empire the karkota Empire the
Chola Empire the maratha empires it was
always Empires
so if you want to truly rise to the top
and become a dominant truly genuinely
dominant civilization democracy is not
going to cut the bill now you will say
that I am contradicting myself because
from episode one I have been saying that
I am a strong believer in democracy I'm
a strong proponent of democracy Now how
can I say that autocracy is the right
way to go
you have to understand that India has
always been a democracy India is the
mother is the birthplace of democracy is
India is the mother of democracy India
always had a hybrid system
at the ground level
at the city Village panchayat level you
had democracy people would elect their
own officials and those officials would
be accountable to the people
but on top they were accountable to the
Emperor or the king
so you had democracy on the ground the
public officials were elected by the
citizens and they were accountable both
to the citizens and to the king
that way you had a lot of autonomy and
Independence and democracy at the ground
level while having an imperial system on
top at the top that way the nation's
interest was always taken care of
because when you have 53 different
opinions you can't take care of the
national interest you can't prioritize a
national interest you're gonna have
politics and compromises that's what
happens in Coalition governments
so India always had this hybrid system
democracy came out of India you even had
Kings who were elected
the Pala Empire in Bengal
look at the history who was the first
king how did he come to power he came to
power after a century of Machinery chaos
and he was elected as king he did not
come to power through a political coup
or a military grab
it was an election
so India has always been Democratic I
believe in democracy democracy is what
empowers the people
but you can't have democracy all the way
at the top
and the the real powers in the world are
not really democracies they are only
pretending to be democracies
so so that's the deal my friends
Daniel Nicholson again
why doesn't the Indian government start
a state-funded corporation like the BBC
that would drive India's narrative
worldwide why does India lack the
political will to do so I I find it very
strange I've been well I've been saying
in public for the past two years but
I've been
wondering about this for more than a
decade why doesn't India have something
like the BBC every nation has a has a
mouthpiece an official mouthpiece the
Americans have a whole bunch of
mouthpieces CNN Fox News
msnbnc all these various Outlets
Washington Post the New York Times the
New Yorker
um all that the British have the BBC
British whatever Corporation they have
the guardian and they have all these
other outlets the Russians have
they they have rt they have Rihanna
vasti they have proud they have Sputnik
the Chinese have CCTV they have Global
times all that the Australians are their
thing the French have their thing the
Germans are their thing the Japanese
have their thing the Koreans have their
thingy on hop and all that India doesn't
have anything
every
even middling little power has its own
political mouthpiece which puts forth
the official perspective
India doesn't have it these days there
are all these self-styled geopolitical
commentators who claim to espouse the
India's national interests and I'm gonna
represent India's national interest in
geopolitics and all that uh listen that
doesn't
let's not talk too much about that my
point is the Indian government needs to
invest in such an organization I just
don't understand why it is not being
done we have this moribund ancient
institution called the doordarshan and
Prasad bharti they I don't even know
what purpose they serve
uh but yes India needs to create
something like the BBC something like
like the Chinese Global times I would
not say Global times which is very like
very unprofessional but yeah something
like the BBC something like the German
DW or or or the Japanese or the Korean
yonhop or the
Russian RT or whatever something of that
level that puts forth India's official
perspective in front of the global
audience
from the perspective of India's national
National interest that's what is
really needed I can't believe the
government has not done this let Twitter
say it's a government of india-funded
organization so what so this is what we
have is that there are various private
news channels
in which they have one or two
geopolitical analysts or Experts of some
kind and they claim that we we represent
India they don't
they don't trust me they don't
so this is something that needs to
happen and I'm really aghast
it's not been done that I don't know why
it's not being done does India like the
like the political win it will India
clearly doesn't lack the money so I'm
not sure what is lacking and I don't
have the answer to that
okay couple of questions Veer Darbar
says
what's your view about the Malaysian
airplane MH370 the plane that
disappeared in 2014 swapnil says the
Malaysian Airlines flight MH370
mysteriously disappeared while traveling
from Kuala Lumpur to Beijing in March
2014. what causes a flight to vanish
from the air surveillance Radars and
what likely caused let this fly led to
this flight going missing with no
recovery
of the fuselage and the black box
interesting question so what happened so
we had this flight uh from Kuala Lumpur
to Beijing which was supposed to go to
Beijing and it disappeared so let's
let's take a look at the map and and see
what where this all happened so we have
Malaysia we have the capital city Kuala
Lumpur over here as you can see and the
flight took off I think late at night it
was it's called what's called a red eye
flight a late night flight and it was
supposed to go all the way in the north
to Beijing so the the plane takes off it
it crosses the Malaysian Peninsula and
it's over the Gulf of Thailand I believe
and it it kind of crosses out of
Indonesian airspace and then
it turned back
we know it turned back it it crossed the
Malaysian Peninsula all over again
I think it flew over Penang I believe or
something then it went into the Malacca
Strait
and somewhere over the Gulf of Thailand
the transponder which is an instrument
of the plane was switched off
sweet
it fell off the radar and this happened
when it was crossing over from the
Malaysian airspace into uh into
eventually what would be I believe
Cambodian or Vietnam is airspace
so at that time neither of these two
Nations was looking at the flight and
that's when the thing was switched off
then it crossed all the way back over
Malaysia it went toward the Malacca
Strait and then there's the mystery as
to where it went
so there are two uh there are two arcs
that are possible one takes it
southwards into the middle of the Indian
Ocean the Deep Indian Ocean Southern
Indian Ocean where obviously there's no
place to land which means it would have
crashed there the other possibility is
that there's another Arc which takes it
all the way into Kazakhstan
so there was this immersive immersed
satellite that kept on pinging the the
airplane and it was able to get some
things back so clearly the plane was
flying for a few more hours and that's
the possible route it could have taken
but it could not tell whether it went
North or South it was only able to
measure the distance so that's how we
have two arcs two possible arcs
that the plane could have taken so the
question is what causes a flight to
vanish from Air surveillance Radars so
you every every commercial plane has
something called a transponder which is
a transmitter and responder transponder
transmit transmission respond and
responding response so uh these uh
commercial uh Radars which track
commercial planes commercial flights
they send a signal periodically to every
aircraft
it's called an interrogation signal it's
it's like you're asking a question
so the plane picks it up and the
transponder responds with us with with
an answer which sends a different set of
data back to the radar which typically
would contain um the the code of a plane
this cork squawk code of the plane and
its altitude
and some other data
so that's how the radar in these Air
Traffic Control uh Towers that's how the
radar knows where each plane is and it's
able to track each plane so if you
switch off the transponder which is what
happened then the plane goes falls off
the radar screen it vanishes from the
radar screen uh from the radar from the
radar screen of a of a commercial air
traffic control tower
but it will still appear on the radar
screen of of your regular radar which is
the military radar so in a military
radar you don't look at the transponder
response or any of those things you
simply send a radio transmission it hits
the plane and the waves reflect back of
this of the skin of the plane and then
it it goes back to the radar and you can
see where the where the aircraft is so
if you have a military radar military
grade radar you can keep on tracking the
plane even if it switches off all the
trans the transporter in any other
instrument
so the thing is that the Malaysians
looks like they did not have a good
radar system military radar system so
the the the plane simply disappeared so
in case it went all the way to
Kazakhstan and North it would have had
to cross Indian airspace and as we know
India is a nation with wonderful
neighbors so we have a very robust and
strong
military radar system so if this
happened then it would have come on
Indian radar Indian military radar Air
Force Radar all that uh as far as we
know it did not happen
so it looks like the plane would have
gone
southwards and made its way all the way
into the heart of the Southern Indian
Ocean and obviously there is no place to
land over there which means it would
have most likely crashed now who did
this why did this happen we still don't
know I believe the the main suspect is
the captain of the plane
Ahmad zahari Shah or something that's
supposed to be his name I don't remember
the exact name you can Google it
um
another possibility is that maybe the
plane was hijacked uh maybe so we don't
quite know what happened and obviously
uh the plane has never been recovered uh
there have been reports that some parts
of a Boeing physiology were found in
reunion or Mauritius or something
or maybe sessions I'm not sure which
place but it's not really conclusive
definitive evidence that it's come from
this particular aircraft itself the
mh370. so it's still a big mystery maybe
the biggest mystery in the history of
Aviation we still don't know what
happened to the aircraft did somebody
hijack the aircraft and take it
somewhere
or did it simply crash into the Indian
Ocean
or or what happened and who did it and
why was it done nobody knows there are
Whispers that some nations would know
about what happened exactly what
happened but obviously there is no
evidence that's available in the public
domain so it's a huge mystery so that's
how a flight vanishes from Air
surveillance Radars by switching up the
transponder but it's still going to be
visible as long as it's in the air to
military radar which doesn't look at the
transponder data at all it simply looks
at the physical evidence of an aircraft
in the air
right next question
online says bro yo bro yo sir please
answer any of the two okay who caused
the highest damage to the world
Anglo-Saxon Crusades turkic invasions
world wars or European colonization
let's take it one by one the Crusades
were not merely Anglo-Saxon they were
the Catholic Crusades so
um
about a thousand years or so before
today uh the Middle East what is
currently Israel and Jerusalem this
region was was uh it was under Arabic
control
uh it was part of the caliphate
so the the Muslims the Arabs were
controlling very in possession of this
region so Jerusalem is the the holy city
and the place where Jesus Christ was
crucified and all that so the Catholic
Church said that this this holy city
should not be in the hands of the of the
Arabs of the Muslims so so the Europeans
the Christians need to go and Conquer it
so this was a way
so this achieved multiple purposes it uh
consolidated the power of the Catholic
Church the Vatican yes uh it also to
some extent for some time ended in
fighting in Europe Europe has this
history of constant Warfare constant in
fighting between the various uh kingdoms
so it brought all the European uh
princes or Kings together for a change
and it gave them a common purpose under
the leadership and authority of the of
the Catholic Church the Catholic church
with the real power in Europe and all
the infighting much of it was actually
orchestrated by the Catholic Church to
maintain its hold and control and power
over Europe so it unified these guys
together and sent them on this big
big Voyage this crusade to liberate
Jerusalem so there were these Crusades
multiple Crusades and there was some
damage done the the fighting typically
happened in the Middle East so it did
not really cause a lot of damage to the
world overall so one can discount the
Crusades the turkic invasions caused
incredible
harm to the world
uh if we look at the the the death toll
in India itself of the turkic occupation
of India it will most likely cross 500
million over seven centuries maybe seven
eight nine centuries at least 500
million Indians would have died you
cannot even imagine such a number maybe
you laugh at me saying this but if you
calculate it properly it will easily
come to 500 million that's the worst
genocide in all history okay and much
more was done in Central Asia so it was
a demic genocide in a physical
extermination of people and a cultural
genocide and a religious genocide and
then you had the the turkic invasions
Arabic invasions of Africa Etc
which enslaved much of Africa and there
was this this slave trade
the Arabic The the Arab mediated African
slave trade in which incredible numbers
of African people men women children
mainly women children and also men of
course we're taken as slaves to the to
the Arabic and turkic world and no trace
of them survives today
so you can imagine what happened so the
the turkic invasions were a horrific
event
definitely in the in the top three
the world wars uh
the world wars caused a lot of damage
I'm not sure what was the total death
toll of the world wars definitely less
than the turkic invarians so turkey
invasions is above world wars definitely
the European colonization so the
European colonization colonization was
one of the most horrific events on all
world history this little Bunch this
little uh
little region Europe eventually took
over the whole world
they colonized North America South
America wiped out the natives eradicated
their culture all all traces of their
history at least 100 million Native
Americans were killed off in North
America who knows how many were killed
in South America
yes uh Asia Africa Africa is still
colonized Africa is still dirt poor why
is it so because it is still actively
being colonized by Europe by European
powers uh so tremendous uh destruction
in Africa all the native cultures were
wiped out of Africa we don't even know
how many people died today Africans
practice foreign religions and they
fight each other for foreign religions
and they they speak foreign languages
and obviously the colonization of India
the British killed off at least a
hundred million Indians at least 100
billion minimum most likely 150 or 200
million that's what the British did in
India so I think when it comes to the
top two it will be the turkey invasions
and the European colonization uh they
both would have very similar death tolls
and similar uh cultural genocide effects
so the most the highest damage to the
world was done by the angle by by the by
the turkic invasions and the European
colonization the world wars are are a
distant third I would say
hardik says recently Vladimir Putin said
that Germany is not a free country it is
occupied by the U.S since World War II
this is the same thing which I say well
it is it is the truth it's a fact so
what impacts does this statement make on
Germans and Europeans not much of an
impact the most see most people don't
think
most people simply
um accept what people in Authority tell
them this includes most Indians this is
something I face on a daily basis I see
it on a daily basis uh so most people
don't think whatever the teachers have
told them whatever the media tells them
whatever the politicians tell them they
simply believe it
and you have the faculty of thinking and
logical analysis but they don't use it
so when somebody says a different thing
they will simply laugh it off they will
not pause for a minute and think about
it what are the facts what is this
person saying they'll simply laugh it
off so I would say that 90 of Europeans
will simply laugh of what Putin says and
they'll say what the hell is he saying
he's an evil guy why should we listen to
him so it won't make much of a
difference obviously there are some
intelligent people out there who
actually use the brain other intelligent
people somehow don't use the brain so
some people will know about it and they
will realize that he is right we know
for a fact that Germany has been under
permanent U.S military occupation since
the end of the second world war their
constitution was written by the
Americans by proxy or not so much by
proxy and
that's how it's been and ever since the
reunification of Germany the the the the
Constitution was applied to East Germany
as well so Germany has been under U.S
occupation since the end of the second
world war so has Italy essentially the
entirety of Western Europe is a big U.S
occupied buffer zone which keeps Russia
away it was designed to keep the USSR
away and after the collapse of the USSR
that buffer zone was expanded by moving
it eastwards the expansion of NATO so
so Putin has said this openly typically
people don't speak about this so he has
said this openly it won't make much of a
difference to Europeans most Europeans
will not think
anything he says they will say it's the
words it's the words of the bad guy
he put in his words that Hitler these
days that's what they say
so it's gonna make not much of a
difference people simply want to take
him seriously and they won't think about
the merits or demerits of what he is
saying based on actual facts on the
ground just look at the map of how many
foreign military bases are on your
territory that is I will tell you that
you are on the form military occupation
but they won't think about it
unfortunate
rakhi says what language was spoken by
the Gypsies in the 17th century I've
been trying to look it up but I only
found that some it was some old
indo-aryan language and its history is
undocumented it was evolved from
Sanskrit in Upper Branch I am writing a
book based on the based in the early
1600s in Greece there's a scene where
some gypsies perform a dance number and
I don't know which language to write
their song in since they were from
Rajasthan and Gujarat will it be all
right if I write in the old western
Rajasthani or marwari language it's not
necessary but I want to have a few lines
to elevate the reading experience see
the gypsies the so-called gypsies the
Romani people they uh
it's a long story I will not go into it
I've spoken about it multiple times uh
many historians will say that they uh
the Romani language is closely related
to Punjabi which is not true the Romani
language is most closely related to
Sindhi Gujarati in Rajasthani marwadi
these are the three modern Indian
languages that come closest through the
Romani language that is spoken by Romani
origin people in Europe
uh and some of the romanis are called
sinti they call themselves which
obviously means Sindhi right so uh so
though if you want to write
um a song lyrics in the gypsy language
the Romanian language I think the best
approximation would either would most
likely be uh marwari or Gujarati or
Cindy one of these three languages and
older versions of that obviously because
they immigrated out of India about a
thousand or so years before today so
Gujarati and Rajasthani Gujarati all
these languages they all originate from
the old old Gujarati language which is
which was a praklative language spoken
about a thousand years ago
so that would be the language that their
ancestors would have spoken and that's
evolved into the present-day Romanian
language so I think you can use marwadi
perhaps as an approximation that would
work reasonably fine
Richa says do humans display Quantum
Behavior since their behavior also
changes in the presence of an observer
yes when you're alone you behave a
certain way and when you have observers
you behave differently so in quantum
mechanics you have particles
you know
um you have particles in quantum
mechanics are described by this
mathematical wave function uh and and
these particles
are in in a superposition of various
States they could be in different places
at the same time but the moment somebody
observe it observes it the wave function
is said to collapse and the particle
resolves into a single state in one
single location so when it's not being
observed it's in a number of states in a
possibly in a number of different
locations at the same time that's the
weirdness of quantum mechanics but when
someone observes it it immediately comes
and resolves itself in one state in one
single location
so that's the quantum behavior of
quantum particles human behavior yeah
when you're alone you behave in a
certain way when people observe you
behave differently that's true but when
no one's observing you you're not in
multiple places at the same time so that
aspect of quantum behavior is not
exhibited by humans we are that way
physically classical objects but yes
interesting question
all right
could you please tell about future light
cone of an event why is it shaped like a
cone how does it divide space-time into
past in future light code okay so um
when you talk about space time it's a
four dimensional fabric we know that
space
we see it we perceive it in three
dimensions length breadth and height
three dimensions of space and then time
is taken as a fourth fourth dimension in
general relativity and these together
make up the four dimensional fabric of
space time so when you want to create a
light cone like you're saying you have
to treat space space itself is a two
dimensional shape because we don't know
how to construct anything in four
dimensions so we uh construct
three-dimensional
uh diagrams of these events and in which
space is taken as a two dimensional
fabric let me put one of these images on
the screen so that you will get some
idea of what I'm okay light cone future
and all that here we are let us do it
so let's take a look at this image
there is a flat sheet over here it's
called the hyper surface of the present
it's actually three dimensional space
and the the vertical Dimension the
vertical axis is the time Dimension so
let's say you are at the Apex of this
cone in the present in this location and
an event happens which let's call it a
flash of light
so the light will travel outwards in
space
at the speed of light so as time goes by
which is the uh vertical axis the y-axis
that where the cone will expand the the
the the the uh
how far the light of that flash goes
will keep on increasing with the uh
passage of time that's why it looks like
a cone so in the future
all of this space
will be uh influenced by that event by
the light that comes from the event as
time goes by so as time goes by the cone
becomes wider and wider if it is right
where you are it's uh the cone has no
size because it's it's just happened
where you are and there is something
called a past light cone itself it
doesn't mean that the light goes back
into the past the past light cone is the
events that have happened in the past
that can possibly influence you and any
event that's outside the past light cone
can in no way possibly influence you
ever
so the past light cone is about the
events that happened in the past that
can possible that could have or have
influenced you and the future light cone
is whatever event you've set off the
flash of Light how far will its
influence go that's what it is about and
that's why it is shaped like a cone
says how to define the solar system what
is the range
so this the sun is our star the sun
gives us light gives us life the nearest
star is Proxima Centauri four point
something light years away
so from that perspective the range of
the solar system is half of that
distance
so uh
the range of the solar system is
essentially
how far the gravitational influence of
the Sun
predominates how far from the Sun itself
so um
there are multiple ways of defining this
so gravity itself is an infinite Force
the force of the gravitational effects
of any object go out into Infinity
but they predominate only up to a
certain extent so when you have a star
in space its gravity will will be
predominant in a certain region Beyond
which the gravity of another star will
become the predominant Force so that is
the range of the solar system now you
have something called the old Cloud Oort
clout let's put that on the screen
Cloud so that could be taken as the
boundary of the solar system it is a
hypothetical spherical region of IC
bodies I see objects it's where the
Comets come from cometary nuclei and
this goes out all the way to more than
one light year most likely up to three
light years away but if you go that far
then you will come under the influence
of a neighboring star most likely there
are approx there are a lot of other
stars in in our neighborhood including
serious proximus Centauri uh tausi Thai
Epsilon iridani and so many more so I
think the uh the range the limit of the
solar system would be about roughly two
light years outwards from the sun which
would be the outer range of the Urt
Cloud that would be the outer boundary
so to say of the solar system
Krishna Das says European Invaders made
false claims of Sati prata devotees
getting crushed under the Wrath in Puri
jagannath Puri and uh we they also
destroy the Native American history by
putting false information like the
Aztecs sacrificed humans by slicing
their chest and offering the still
beating heart to the deities and so on
uh yeah it's possible it's possible see
the history of South America as we know
it is the history that was written by
the colonizers
the native records of their own history
do not survive they were all destroyed
by the missionaries by the corner by the
colonizers uh they had their own script
they had their own language it's all
been destroyed in most parts of South
America the natives don't even speak
their native languages anymore they
speak Spanish
in Brazil they speak Portuguese
so it's been a horrific cultural
genocide even the languages have been
wiped out and all the writing has been
destroyed which means there is nowhere
to decipher the script
in in some cases
uh so whatever we know of their past of
their history is whatever the European
colonizers and missionaries have written
about it so clearly there's going to be
a lot of atrocity literature which would
solve the purpose of justifying the
European colonization of the Americas
the the the the argument will be that
they were so primitive and Savage and
violent that the colonization was a
great Boon for them in the imposition of
Christianity was a civilizing mission
that is what European historiography
always does whether it is in the
Americas whether it's in India or
anywhere else Africa or anywhere else
so we know that there was that they had
these customs of
well of of uh sacrificing people now if
you look at statues and depictions of
goddess Kali goddess Durga she's
depicted these goddesses are depicted
with uh Garland of severe human heads
does it mean that Indians sacrificed
ritual sacrifice and all that no
these goddesses represent the victory of
good over evil and the garlands of heads
the garden of heads is the heads heads
of evildoers of evil people who deserve
who who would have deserved to be put to
death so in every civilization in every
culture in every nation you historically
you've had the death penalty
you do certain things you cross a
certain line you're gonna be put to
death and and often you would have a
prisoners of War
who would be put to death for whatever
reason
sometimes in war you don't take
prisoners right you have to do some this
has happened everywhere so
oftentimes it's executions of of enemies
or of criminals but then it it gets
maybe they would do it once a year on
top of the pyramid and that's what the
Europeans saw and then that's what they
portrait is is being uh executions of
ritual uh religious executions of of uh
innocent people we don't know what quite
happened but it's a very significant
possibility because you cannot trust
what the Europeans have been saying
because they colonized and destroyed all
these places and then they wrote the
history so the history will obviously be
self-serving history we know what they
have done to India the kind of History
they wrote about India
in
Mexico Etc which were racks of skulls
severe heads so this is an example
so you have some actual evidence of that
of uh these racks of head constructed
this is in Mexico City you can see that
uh the native architecture has been
superimposed by Colonial architecture
religious architecture you know and many
of these somalis are simply uh
you know they're simply carvings of
skulls into rock not actual skulls in
rock you can see lots of those these
things
um over here as well over here as well
these are not real skulls
and uh some of it would have looked like
that so some of it would have happened
what was the purpose of it was it actual
executions of criminals which happened
once a year or so which these people
witnessed the Europeans witness and then
blew out of proportion we don't know but
I would be very cautious about trusting
anything the Europeans wrote about the
people they conquered and destroyed
Mazar says if India were to become an
economic superpower and also unite like
the EU in the future how would the
public perception of historical figures
such as Jinnah nehru and Gandhi be
impacted who played pivotal roles in the
partition of the Indian subcontinent and
how would Freedom Fighters like netaji
Bose and others be viewed who sacrificed
their lives of the motherland see public
perception of historical figures is an
evolving thing it keeps evolving
uh we know very well see it's happening
right now the perception of people like
is changing to some extent as we speak
right now
Indian kids are taught in school College
University that people like nehru and
Gandhi were superheroes they were Saints
it's it's not history that you're taught
it's hate geography that you're tall
taught fake embellished history that
that hero worships these people
the truth is that people like were
instrumental in helping the British and
the West achieve its geopolitical their
geopolitical aims by partitioning India
the people of India were never consulted
into about whether they wanted a
partition or not
but there were these fake elections and
all in 1946 held under foreign
occupation which have which which are
cannot be recognized as a democratic
process by any means whatsoever
so uh the public
uh perception of these people will
change over time it's an evolving uh
thing
if India let's say a hundred years from
now India is reunified which is a
significant possibility which is very
strong possibility well in a hundred
years time the historians from 100 years
from now over descendants will
definitely look at these historical
figures hopefully from a much more
realistic and evidence-based perspective
right now we are taught the opinions of
certain so-called historians but let's
see the facts who did what if you look
at it that way a whole different story
emerges anybody with half a brain can
see that so I think over time
the in the contributions of these
individuals will be reevaluated and
hopefully their their their their their
careers will be viewed from a more
realistic perspective including Heroes
like nitaji Subhash Chandra Bose who
sacrificed their lives for the
motherland
okay I think we are almost at the end of
today's uh
let's take a couple of more questions
um
a big says when why everything bad about
India is India but anything good from
India is South Asian what is this and
what is the West trying to achieve by
drought by downplaying India everywhere
okay what is this so-called South Asia
let's take a look at the map let's take
a look at the map of Asia
first of all there's no such thing as
Asia it's Eurasia Europe is not some
separate entity so it's it's this giant
continent called Eurasia they have
separated Europe somehow it's an
imaginary separation like the like the
imaginary imaginary boundaries that dogs
have on the streets this group of dogs
has this region and there's an imaginary
boundary somewhere that's another group
of dogs over here and if a dog crosses
this imaginary boundary the other other
group starts barking at him so that's
kind of what they've done between Europe
and Asia imaginary boundary it's just
one continent Eurasia now if you want to
talk about the south of Asia it would
most likely be Indonesia and papanagini
because Indonesia is part of Asia
so um
so we don't
so so that's how it is so it's a fake
nomenclature fake terminology that has
been constructed South Asia the correct
terminology is the Indian subcontinent
that's what it has historically been
called so anybody who uses the term
South Asia I I find that person very
suspicious why I wonder what the real
motives are this is an artificial term
coined by the West to uh to take away
for whatever is good from India so
whenever something good happens like
like let's say this movie RR won an
Oscar
in the west it was being portrayed is a
South Asian movie in South Asian Cinema
not Indian and there was even this this
uh reporter who was talking to one of
the heroes one of the main actors and
calling it a South Asian movie and he
was he had to respond back to her two
three times saying it's not a South
Asian movies in Indian movie
so anything good that comes out of India
they will portray it as a South Asian
thing but when something bad has to be
spoken about they'll say it's Indian
so when they want to report about some
fake attack
on a church they will say it happened in
India it's not a South Asian phenomenon
when something bad happens outside of
India
which has its origin within Pakistan for
instance like those grooming gangs in
the UK they will say it's South Asian
government gangs even though there's not
a single Indian in there Indian religion
person they're all Pakistani origin
people
of course Pakistan itself originated 70
years ago but whatever all those people
hail from Pakistan
but they will call it South Asian
grooming gangs so it is a deliberate
thing
whatever good comes out of India they
want to ascribe it to the whole of the
region and including Pakistan but if
anything bad is there they want to
pinpoint it down to India only
so this is all about maligning India and
not letting the rest of the world know
what's good about India if anything good
happens they will say it's it's
collectively Southaven
so yeah uh it's jealousy
it's jealousy the fact is that India is
the only nation that is on track in this
Century to surpass the US it's not going
to happen next year next week next
decade by 2050 2016 India is going to go
ahead of the U.S economically militarily
we will see so by 2050 China will no
longer be number two China will be
number three
and by 2060 or so the latest India will
surpass the US India is the future this
is not the Asian Century or the Chinese
Century this is the Indian century and
there's a huge amount of jealousy in the
west but we ruled over you for more than
two centuries we tried our best to
totally destroy you and you have
rebounded and you're going to surpass us
and this is something they're not able
to swallow and Digest
so there's a huge amount of jealousy
it's a big amount of hatred towards
India and that's why they use all these
terms to downplay anything good that
comes out of India and to downplay any
of India's achievements that is the
reason why this term this fake term has
been invented
by the West whatever the West is you can
guess what it is
okay let's take some questions from the
live chat I have many more questions
which I will not be able to take as
usual but let's take a few questions
from the live chat before we wrap this
episode up if you have any questions
please let me know in the live chat
Aditya says are Arabs of Indian origin
most likely they are not as of Indian
origin the Arabs are of of Semitic
origin the Semitic people
um so
it's a different language family
the Indian language family is very
different from the Semitic language
family the Semitic language is
the two major language groups are Arabic
and Hebrew the Arabs and Jews are
actually brothers
close relatives so the Arabs are not of
Indian origin at least from the
perspective of the language families
genetically you will find Indian
genetics among the Arabs from the
matrilineal lineages because lots of
Indian women were taken as slaves
in the past 1000 Years out of India and
they have descendants in in the Arabic
countries you see lots of Arabs who look
very similar to Indians
but yeah that's the reason for that
um
Joseph why do most societies disregard
women and treat women like dogs I am no
male feminist by any stretch but I find
it odd and disgusting that many
societies treat women like trash I agree
that many societies treat women like
Crush
and in India also in some to some extent
some of it is there
now historically
India has not never been like this
historically Indians India treated women
extraordinary well Indians worship women
right and then we have we have people
like Veer dasu come and say things about
that
in the past 1000 Years foreign culture
came into India and foreign practices
came into India that's how in some
sections of Indian Society women are
treated very badly
and if in yeah all that now
when it comes to the abrahamic view of
women women are inferior to men in the
academic worldview that's why
historically in Europe women were
property women had no rights uh in the
Arabic and turkic World also women even
now have less rights than than men so
it's a cultural thing it's a cultural
thing and it it it all comes down to
culture it all boys boils down to
culture so the abrahamic religions treat
women is inferior
to men
but the dharmic culture Indian culture
does not treat women does not see women
as inferior
but because of the infiltration and
influx of an imposition of abrahamic
culture on India to some extent over the
past 1000 Years such practices will have
unfortunately crept into India as well
so I personally myself agree with you
that uh but it's horrible it's
disgusting it's despicable that women
are treated differently and as inferior
human beings In some cultures which is
obviously unacceptable by any stretch of
the imagination no civilized society you
cannot be a civilized society if you
treat women like this I mean it has to
go without saying
all right let's take a couple more
questions
um let me see let's see who all is there
um
uh
let's take some interesting questions
why should I not nuke Pakistan well I
don't believe in nuking anybody these
see India and Pakistan obviously have
differences and Pakistan is unfinished
business Pakistan is our ancestral
territory we will take it back
eventually
we don't want to Nuke anyone the people
who live in Pakistan they may hate India
but listen they're also human beings and
it's not their fault so we will not nuke
them the best way to win
is to win without fighting
best way to win is to
is to make the situation such that
Victory is inevitable it simply falls
into your lap
and the military means have to be the
last means and among the military means
the nuclear means have to be taboo
because it's a disaster so yes please
don't do new Pakistan I'm sure you have
the means to Nuke Pakistan please don't
do it sir please don't do it thank you
um um
okay let's see this is by Shivam
any news on thorium-based nuclear
reactors in India and or recent progress
to getting there I am not sure about
what the progress is like uh we know we
are told
that India has the world's most advanced
thorium nuclear
reactor program but I'm not sure if you
have any I mean what the progress has
been like maybe it's kept Under Wraps
because such things should not well you
know you should information about
sensitive matter should be given out on
a need to know basis so maybe so so I
don't really know what the status is but
there has there has been any big
breakthrough so ideally we would want
all of our nuclear reaters to be powered
by thorium because thorium is available
in such incredible abundance in India
but obviously you would have to
uh device means of extracting the
thorium from the monozyte Sands that are
available on the west coast of India
India has about a quarter of the entire
planets thorium reserves so it makes
sense for India to invest in thorium
technology but I don't know where it has
reached thus far it's a good question
maybe I should
maybe I should uh reach out to somebody
who would know about this and and
perhaps do a podcast or something all
right let's do one last question
one last question do we have any
interesting question Shivam says
shouldn't be exposed I agree sir I agree
have you seen Rocket Boys I haven't seen
Rocket Boys
Ajay says what's the what's the dragon
rapid Dragon launching missile launching
system
can it be integrated I I don't know what
it is I've not heard of it
should I have heard of it I'm not sure I
will I will
I will look it up I will not do the
research on live but I will look it up
maybe next time you can ask same
question in the comments next time and I
will I'll take it up so I will look into
this thank you for the question I
appreciate that
why are the number of animals increasing
behind me ah yes animals are
proliferating I we would like to have
more animals in the environment
you know so this this this this horse
this is elephant over here there are
these Shanghai deer here there's a
rhinoceros here and I would like to
increase this this Menagerie a little
bit more
right right
okay let's see do we have one more
question
um
what's India's uh permanency from the
U.S U.N security Council
um listen when you say that all
countries except China are in agreement
with India's bid that's not really true
the Americans know that China will
opposite that's why they are saying
verbally that we will support India's
bid if China suddenly agrees the
Americans will Now launch objections
okay so nobody wants to give up the
power that they have so let's stop
talking about this permanent seat in the
U.N security Council and let's build
some genuine power let's become so
powerful that the U.N security Council
doesn't even matter anymore
Indians
see I'm not blaming anybody in or
pointing figures at anybody in specific
but Indians we don't understand what
power is we don't understand how
geopolitics works all these all these
positions and accolades and honors we
don't need them what we really need is
power
and and big economy and military
strength that's what gives you real
power and influence in the world and
once you have that all these little
fancy things like a permanent seat and
all they don't matter so that is what
India needs to focus on build the
economy
focus on manufacturing become the
largest economy in the world in the next
by 2050 hopefully and build a military
that is proportional to that economic
strength that's what India needs to
focus on and with that I'm going to end
this
episode of the year of the of the ask of
the Oscar video show thank you very much
for all your questions thank you for
watching and I will see you in the next
episode hopefully soon enough until then
take care
see you